Steven Cody Thaller

(305) 586 3756 | Renton, WA | stevencthaller@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

SUMMARY

I am a driven and determined Full-Stack Developer excited to move from teaching to creating! I earned a Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering from Florida International University and moved to the Seattle area to pursue my dream of becoming a software developer. I have experience building full-stack applications in C# with the ASP.NET MVC framework, Python with the Django framework, and JavaScript/TypeScript using MERN/MEAN technologies, and have spent the past nearly two years leading and teaching others to do the same.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React
- C#
- Entity
- .NET
- ASP.NET MVC
- MySQL
- Python

- Django
- Flask
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- MongoDB
- Express
- Angular

- Node.js
- Github
- HTML5
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JQuery
- AJAX

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Sir_Saltimus (WIP) | https://github.com/StevenCThaller/Sir_Saltimus

2021

- Web application built for a Twitch streamer. Allows for creating stream schedules, embedded video, and a forum section (this is still WIP).
- Implemented React to create a single-page application (SPA), to query an API built in ASP.NET.
- Twitch login using Auth0

RepairSage | https://314solutions.info

2019

- Implemented Angular to create a single-page application (SPA) allowing automobile repair shops to handle all aspects of scheduling repairs.
- Incorporates drag and drop capabilities, file upload/download, and dynamic calculations to provide a seamless experience for technicians.
- Adapted an Express app in Node.js with MongoDB to pass data between the SPA and our server by structuring our back-end as a RESTful API.

Wedding Stasher | https://github.com/StevenCThaller/WeddingStasher

2021

- Created for a family friend for their wedding. It gives guests the ability to scan a QR code at their table, and submit photos and videos to a "digital guest book."
- Implemented an ASP.NET back-end, with vanilla JavaScript on the front end.
- Utilized Amazon S3 file storage for image/video uploads. You may privately request the url of the deployed version.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coding Dojo | Bellevue, WA

Acting West Coast Regional Lead Instructor

October 2021 - Present

- In addition to my normal Head Instructor duties, manage and assist all instructors in the West Region for the company.
- Run training events for instructors, as well as marketing and welcome events for new students.
- Assist in managing the development of our in-house Discord Bot for student server management.

<u>Head Instructor</u> April 2021 - Present

- Perform the duties expected of Web Development Instructor (listed below)
- Manage and train other Instructors and Teaching Assistants

- Collaborate and improve on new and existing Standard Operating Procedures to be incorporated company-wide
- Assist in the development of a Discord Bot to facilitate the management of students and our Discord server (Discord.js on a Node.js server).

Web Development Instructor

August 2019 - April 2021

- Lead instruction for all stacks (Web Fundamentals, Python (Django, Flask), C# (ASP.NET), MEAN, and MERN
- Prepare students for success by providing coaching in all aspects of their journey towards becoming critical thinkers and problem solvers
- Day to day instruction of students, following a well-curated curriculum, supplemented with my own professional experiences
- Implement state law policies relating to career/vocational schools, such as enforcing student attendance, the grading of assignments, etc.
- Gather and report on student metrics
- Participate in occasional product and curriculum development, as well as curriculum refinement
- Due to the current COVID-19 Pandemic, I have also successfully transitioned to working fully remote

Web Development Teaching Assistant

June 2019 - August 2019

- Assisted instructors in teaching web development using various languages and technologies
- Conduct code reviews with on-site students
- Shadow and support current Instructors
- Frequent check-ins with students (roughly every 20 minutes) to identify what students are working on, and how to support their learning

Freelance Web Developer | RepairSage | Seattle, WA

March 2019 - August 2019

- Worked as part of a small development team to create an enterprise level, scalable web application for scheduling automobile repairs.
- Worked extensively on responsive styling for desktop, tablet, and smartphone use.
- Regularly collaborated with both the client and other developer to achieve our goals in building our application.

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Developer Certificate | Bellevue, WA

2019

- Immersive Full-Stack Training Program in Python, C#, and MEAN
- Triple Blackbelt Graduated with highest honors

Florida International University | Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering | Miami, FL

2018

- Concentrations in Data System Software and Network Engineering
- Additional focus in Embedded Systems